<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Projects on TJ</title>
    <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Projects on TJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cosmetic Product Development (ML)</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>The growing popularity of natural ingredient-based cosmetics, driven by consumer awareness of health and environmental benefits, has propelled a leading Toronto manufacturer to success in creating products for various brands and launching its own natural ingredient-focused line. This project aims to develop a data-driven model that recommends suitable natural ingredients for new cosmetic products based on customer ratings and reviews from Amazon. By utilizing the vast user-generated data on Amazon, the model will help the sponsor company understand consumer preferences, innovate highly desired products, and ultimately boost sales and customer satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northwind Traders Dashboard (Tableau &amp; BigQuery)</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Utilizing Tableau&amp;rsquo;s robust visualization capabilities, a comprehensive Key Performance Indicator (KPI) dashboard was developed for Northwind Traders. Northwind Traders is an international import and export company, specializing in providing high-quality food products to a broad spectrum of businesses across the globe. The objective of the dashboard was to offer a rapid understanding of the company&amp;rsquo;s performance in crucial areas, such as sales trends, product performance, principal clients, and shipping costs. Designed to accommodate and evolve with the influx of new data, the dashboard promises dynamic and timely insights for the executive team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter Projects Success Prediction (ML)</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Kickstarter is a popular crowdfunding platform that has enabled many individuals and organizations to bring their creative projects to life. Understanding the success factors of Kickstarter projects is crucial for both creators and investors, as it can help them make better decisions and increase their chances of success. Our study takes a step towards achieving this goal by exploring the effectiveness of different models in predicting the outcome of Kickstarter projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Stock Prices Time Series Analysis (Excel: Moving Average, R: ARIMA)</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The objective of this analysis is to do the forecasting analysis on the price of two companies ( Costco Wholesale company (COST) and Coca-Cola (KO) from the previous 252 data period. Performing by using three separate forecasting models:
Exponential smoothing performed the short-term forecasting. Weight moving average to complete the long-term forecasting for the following four periods. ARIMA to make a long-term forecast for the next three months&amp;rsquo; stock price and to forecast the wine price for the next ten years in the dry_wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefit-Cost Analysis of Dam Construction Projects (Excel: Monte Carlo Simulation &amp; Chi-Squared Test))</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The purpose of this analysis is to apply benefit-cost analysis to two construction projects, Dam 1 in Southwest Georgia and Dam 2 in North Carolina, in order to support the corporation in determining which project provides the greatest benefit. By analyzing six benefit categories (improved navigation, hydroelectric power, fish and wildlife, recreation, flood control, and commercial development of the area), as well as two cost areas (Annualized capital cost and operations and maintenance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Driven by my passion for analytics and data science, I am currently pursuing a Master’s degree in Analytics from Northeastern University, Boston. Armed with a B.E. in Information and Communication Engineering from Chulalongkorn University, Thailand, I bring a unique blend of business acumen and technical prowess.
I have honed my skills working across various sectors. In my recent role as a Business Intelligence Analyst at Veolia North America, I deployed data modeling techniques, designed ELT workflows, and standardized reports, significantly improving efficiency and business processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teerajate2.github.io/TJ_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
Platform URL Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/teerajate-v-120b7822b Github: https://github.com/Teerajate2 Tableau: https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/teerajate.vantanasiri3469 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
